unison.audio 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy - Unison

### **1\. Introduction**

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which [www.unison.audio](https://www.unison.audio/) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected through this website (“Site” or “Unison”). We respect your privacy and adhere to our privacy law obligations. We do not gather any personal information from you that you do not provide voluntarily, and we will never sell or trade your personal information.   

### **2\. Application**

This Privacy Policy applies to the Unison Site and its content and services (“Services”). It should be read in combination with the Unison Terms of Use and these documents together control the relationship between you and us.

### **3\. Who is responsible for personal information collected on the Site?**

The Unison webmaster is the Site owner and operator, and is responsible for the Site’s processing of your personal data and may be contacted at [support@unison.audio](mailto:support@unison.audio?subject=).      

### **4\. What is personal information?**

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual, as defined by applicable law. It is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you. 

### **5\. Protection of minors and COPPA**

This Site is not directed to children under the age of 13 years and we do not intentionally collect, store or in any way use personal information from children younger than 13 years.  You must be 18 years of age or older in order to register for a Unison account, or over 13 years of age and have the consent and supervision or your parent or guardian. In cases where you have authorized a minor (someone under 18 years of age) to use the Site or Services, you acknowledge and agree that you are fully responsible for: (i) the online conduct of such minor; (ii) controlling the minor’s access to and use of the Site or Services; and (iii) the consequences of any misuse by the minor.

### **6\. What personal information do we collect?**

If you contact us by email, we collect your email address. We also collect any information you choose to disclose in the text of any message to us. 

We collect your name, email address, telephone number, location(s), language(s), username and password if you register with us.

Payments are processed by third party providers of payment processing such as PayPal so we do not directly retain your banking and credit card details. 

We may also collect your personal information if shared by you from other social applications, services or websites. 

We may also collect any details you provide to us voluntarily, for example your profile details as an Artist or anything you mention in a review as a Student.

In the course of your use of the Site we may also collect your IP address, which may constitute personal information in some circumstances. We may also collect non-personal statistical information on Site usage, entry and exit pages and so on.

### **7\. How do we collect personal information?**

The main ways we collect personal information from you are through:

Registering you for a Unison account;

Processing your transactions such as collecting payments for sound banks and other products.

Uploading your content, for example by posting a review; or

Information you provide voluntarily by sending us an email.

In the normal course of browsing the site, we may also collect usage information such as your IP address, browser type, language settings, and the URLs of the referring and exit pages. We can also keep track of how much time you spend on the Site and what links you click on while visiting Unison.

### **8\. If you choose not to provide personal information**

You always have the choice to not provide us with your personal information. However, it may not be possible to make full or proper use of the Site if your personal information is not provided to us.

### **9\. Storage and usage of your personal information**

We may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

To register you for a Unison account

Payment processing

Day to day general Site operations 

Publish your content such as a review and so forth

Improving customer service and the Site: For example, we may use feedback you provide to improve the functionality and performance of the Site; and

Sending emails with general information about special offers and promotions, or other Site news and updates.

We do not share your personal information with any third parties, except to the extent necessary to assist you in relation to a legitimate business purpose as listed above. 

### **10\. Social media**

The Site interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, SoundCloud, Instagram, YouTube, Twitter and so forth. If you use the Site in conjunction with your social media accounts you are sharing information with these social media sites, and information you share may also be governed by their privacy policies. You are advised to inform yourself of all applicable privacy policies and to modify your privacy settings with third party social media websites/apps in order to protect your personal information. 

### **11\. Sharing your personal information with third parties**

We do not sell, trade, or rent personal information to third parties. We may use third party service providers in association with the Site, for example Google for website analytics and Stripe for payment processing. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission by agreeing to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to share your personal information in the future if it becomes necessary to do so in order for us to fulfill a legitimate business purpose but will only do so where the third party concerned has agreed to protect such information with appropriate privacy practices that conform with the requirements of privacy law.

### **12\. Cookies**

We do use cookies on the Site. Cookies are small text files stored on your computer. We use both permanent cookies and session cookies. If you don’t want to allow permanent cookies, you can select the option to deactivate permanent cookies in your browser. The data stored in session cookies are only valid for the current visit. If you deactivate session cookies, we cannot guarantee that you will be able to make full or proper use of our Site and Services.

### **13\. Google Analytics**

The Site makes use of Google Analytics. Google Analytics is Google’s analytics tool that helps website and app owners to understand how their visitors engage with their properties. Google Analytics may receive and record non-personal information from cookies, server logs, and similar technology from your browser or mobile device, including your IP address. This is controlled by Google as a third party and is not under our direct control. [Learn more about Analytics cookies and privacy information.](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage) By using the Site and Services you are consenting to this use of Google cookies and related technology.

### **14\. Non-personal identification information**

We use anonymous web usage information to analyze how people use this site and to help direct improvements for the site. We aggregate this information in a way that does not identify you personally. We may share this aggregate data with our affiliates, agents, and other third-parties with which we have a business relationship. We will not sell this information.

### **15\. Security**

The Site is professionally hosted and uses appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information. For example, we make use of SSL digital certificates and encryption. However, transmitting information over the Internet is generally not completely secure, and we can’t guarantee the security of your data. Any data you transmit is at your own risk.

### **16\. Retention of personal information**

Your personal information will only be retained for as long as it is needed to operate your account and to meet the requirements of business record retention requirements. This is usually a minimum of seven (7) years. 

### **17\. Sharing your personal information**

We do not sell, trade, or rent personal identification information to third parties. We may use third party service providers in association with the Site, for example Stripe for payment processing or Google for website analytics. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission by agreeing to this Privacy Policy. We do not sell personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes.

### **18\. Links to external websites**

This Site may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party websites. We encourage all users to be aware when they leave this Site and to read the privacy statements of websites that collect personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected directly by us on Unison. 

### **19\. Cross-border disclosure of your information**

The Site is operated in Canada (CAN) and hosted securely by a professional service provider in Canada. This means your use of the Site may lead to your personal information being transmitted to Canada. We will, where practicable, advise you of the countries in which any overseas recipients are located. By providing your personal information in this way, you consent to the disclosure of your personal information to any such overseas recipients. In transferring information that we collect from you to locations outside of Canada, we will only transfer personal data to an overseas recipient where: (1) the country is one which is considered to provide an adequate level of data protection or (2) the personal data is transferred to a Canadian company which has signed up to the Safe Harbor scheme or (3) the personal information is transferred to a company which is required by contract to deal with the information as instructed and with appropriate security. If you have any concerns in relation to such transfers, you should not use the Internet as a means of communication with us. By providing your personal information to us, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

### **20\. Disclaimer and disclosure**

We take reasonable steps to make sure that your information is treated and stored securely. Unfortunately, the sending of information via the Internet is not totally secure and on occasion such information can be intercepted. We cannot guarantee the security of personal information that you choose to send us electronically and sending such information is entirely at your own risk. Unison disclaims all liability for any interception or interruption of any Internet transmissions or any changes to or losses of data, including personal information. Further, if you are located outside of Canada, you acknowledge and agree that any information you provide to us will be transferred to Canada. If you are located inside Canada, you acknowledge and agree that any information you provide to us may be transferred to outside Canada by a Unison service provider such as Google or Stripe. By using the Site, or providing us with any information, you consent to such transfers. 

### **21\. Your acceptance of these terms**

Your use constitutes acceptance. This means that by using the Site you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

### **22\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post any changes on this page as soon as they go into effect. By accessing this website after we make any such changes to this Privacy Policy, you are deemed to have accepted such changes. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

### **23\. Accessing, updating or correcting your personal information**

You may inform us of any changes in your personal information, and in accordance with our obligations to provide you with best practice treatment of personal information, we will update or delete your data accordingly. You can also login to your account yourself and edit your registration information. (If you register with us through Facebook you will need to use Facebook to manage your profile.) 

### **24\. Users who do not want marketing communications from us**

We ask all users to provide a valid email address. Please note there may be some circumstances where may need to terminate some or all of your account services if we cannot communicate with you by email. You have the option to unsubscribe from our emails.

### **25\. Disclosure of your personal information for legal reasons**

To the extent permitted by law, we may disclose the information that we collect (i) when required by law, court order, or other government or law enforcement authority or regulatory agency; or (ii) whenever we believe that disclosing such information is necessary or advisable, for example, to protect our rights, property, or safety, or those of others.

### **26\. Business or asset transfer or Sale**

Unison may be sold, might sell or buy businesses or assets of businesses, or may merge with another business. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that Unison or substantially all the assets of Unison are transferred, customer information may well be one of the transferred assets. We will make reasonable effort to provide notice on the Site and to notify you via email to the most recent email address that you have provided to us of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

### **27\. Lodging a complaint**

If you believe we have not met our obligations with regards to your personal information, please contact us at [support@unison.audio](mailto:support@unison.audio?subject=). We treat such matters seriously. We will investigate as a priority, and will keep you informed as to the progress and outcome of our investigation. 

### **28\. How to contact us**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@unison.audio](mailto:support@unison.audio?subject=). 

**This document was last updated on 7** **th** **June 2018 and is the most up to date version of our Privacy Policy.**
